## Keimari Diaz-Welborn

Oviedo, FL 32765 | (407) 765-7197 | <u>Keimari@att.net</u> linkedin.com/in/keimari-diaz-welborn

# **Instructional Designer**

Experienced Learning and Development Professional with a demonstrated history in the telecommunications industry. Highly skilled in Business Process Improvement, Customer Satisfaction, Client Relations, Presentations, Team Building, Leadership, and Change Management. Proven success in providing instruction in face-to-face, Microsoft Teams, and Zoom/Webex settings. Bilingual (Spanish) operations professional who consistently bolsters business objectives.

## **Core Competencies**

Project Management | Project Planning (Agile) | Risk Management | Resource Coordination

Process Improvement | Relationship Management | Team Management | Analytical | Adult Learning

| Presentations | Critical Thinking

#### **Technical Skills**

WordPress | Vyond | Articulate 360 | Adobe Creative Suite | Microsoft 365 | Agile Methodology | Design Thinking | ADDIE | Storyline | Camtasia | SharePoint/OneDrive

## **Professional Experience**

**AT&T**, Orlando, FL **May 2022 - Dec 2023** 

## Sr. Training Manager of Design/Project Manager

Designed/developed training, eLearning modules, and instructor-led training for over 160,000+ employees, 231 million customers, and \$401 billion in assets.

- Implemented Agile Project Management principles for Learning & Development focused on communication, collaboration, and prototyping/iterations.
  - Instituted daily team stand-up and weekly client status meetings, ensuring awareness of process, status, and collaborating when necessary to keep projects on track.
  - Guided designers through design thinking sessions to work collaboratively with others for the best learning solution/product.
  - Set up working sessions between clients/designers to collaborate on content prototypes, eliminating unnecessary rework.
- Excelled as lead project manager and designer/developer, utilizing Agile project management and a global content strategy.
  - Led project/designed simulations, providing new hires with a realistic experience on systems used in production with a 13% increase in performance metrics.
  - Maintained records, reports, and data using MS Office products.
  - Using problem-solving skills to review, research, and manage concerns that arose from designers not having the necessary resources and removing those roadblocks promptly.
  - Managed quality assurance of each storyboard to ensure the accuracy of workflow and documentation was thorough, with essential details.
  - Peer-reviewed each storyboard and provided constructive feedback to improve learner engagement and system knowledge.
  - Developed training and implemented storyboard standards, guidelines, and procedures to improve the consistency of 62 system simulations.

- Conducted weekly meetings with designers as working sessions to develop ideas to elevate simulations, review the benefits of implementing them, and improve product quality.
- Reduced maintenance hours in 2022/2023.
  - Achieved an additional 25% reduction in maintenance hours with all content in one WordPress site and only edited one global page.
  - Instituted weekly team stand-up and weekly client status meetings, ensuring awareness of process and status, and collaborating when necessary to keep maintenance requests on track.
  - Created spreadsheets with all course components, timing, category, and locations to enable maintenance request completion within a bi-weekly timeframe.
  - Maintained a catalog of over 7,000 images on utilizing WordPress to enable a one-time replacement for a global image or link in all locations in all content.
- Mentored new team members as the tools and systems expert, enabling multiple members to be 100% productive within six weeks.

Keimari Diaz-Welborn Keimari@att.net Page 2

#### Sr. Training Manager of Design, Orlando, FL

October 2019 - May 2022

Designed/developed training, eLearning modules, and instructor-led training for multiple business organizations, resulting in a 15% increase in employee satisfaction with training programs.

- Designed and developed content for multiple lines of business covering soft skills, hard skills, and technical systems with adult learning principles in mind.
- Collaborated with the internal systems development team on project coordination, including the kickoff, needs assessment, planning, design thinking, and validation sessions.
- Drove innovation and emerging technologies to improve efficiency and enhance engagement.
- Maintained 26 WordPress templates for a team of 12 designers to develop consistent-looking content for all sales and distribution new hire courses.

## Sr. Training Manager of Delivery, Orlando, FL

May 2008 - October 2019

Championed AT&T's efforts to attract, develop, mentor, and retain top talent by focusing on designing, developing, and implementing high-quality training programs and solutions to optimize performance management, leadership development, employee assessment, and succession planning.

- Onboarded new hire agents and reviewed the compensation portal to highlight the company's benefits.
- Facilitated training deliverables face-to-face and virtual training, creating the presentation of content that is engaging and fun.
- Facilitated workshops covering systems enhancements, customer service soft skills, and leadership development.
- Provided one-on-one coaching for learner skills improvement.
- Analyzed and collected new hires' performance metrics to capture 30-, 60-, and 90-day results.
- Communicated with peer groups, working adaptively to solve scheduling conflicts, classroom, and any unforeseen situations.

#### **Education**

Associate of Arts - AA, Liberal Arts Seminole State College, Sanford, FL

## Certifications

Become a Full-Stack Web Developer | Articulate Storyline Essential | Gamification of Learning | Instructional Design | Learning Design Thinking | Agile PG/PM: Agile Development Strategic